<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAM-Chem | Ka Ming Fung, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/tags/cam-chem/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/tags/cam-chem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CAM-Chem</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/media/icon_hu14322561806154635754.png</url>
      <title>CAM-Chem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/tags/cam-chem/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the interinfluence of fertilizer-induced ammonia emission, nitrogen deposition, and aerosol radiative effects using modified CESM2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Codes are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_NH3/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_NH3/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring dimethyl sulfide (DMS) oxidation and implications for global aerosol radiative forcing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Codes are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_Heald_DMS/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_Heald_DMS/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responses of surface ozone to future agricultural ammonia emissions and subsequent nitrogen deposition through terrestrial ecosystem changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/liu-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/liu-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CESM The Atmosphere, Whole Atmosphere, and Chemistry-Climate Working Group Meeting 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2021-02-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2021-02-cam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring natural aerosol formation from DMS oxidation and implications for aerosol forcing&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU Fall Meeting 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2020-12-agu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:51854/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2020-12-agu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring natural aerosol formation from DMS oxidation and implications for aerosol forcing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atmospheric aerosol influences the Earth&amp;rsquo;s overall radiative balance, both directly via scattering and absorbing insolation or outgoing radiation reflected by the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface, and indirectly through promoting cloud formation and changing cloud properties. To quantify the radiative forcing requires the comparison of the net radiative budgets of a &amp;quot;polluted&amp;quot; atmosphere versus a &amp;quot;cleaner&amp;quot; preindustrial one. The accurate determination of aerosol radiative forcing thus partly depends on our ability to model the poorly understood preindustrial atmosphere. Here, we focus on modeling the oxidation of dimethyl sulfide (DMS) – a primary natural precursor of non-sea-salt sulfate. Based on previous laboratory studies, we extend the simple DMS oxidation scheme used in the Community Atmospheric Model with chemistry (CAM-chem) version 6 (and similarly in many global ESMs) by adding new gas- and aqueous-phase reactions and including intermediate compounds, e.g., methanesulfonic acid (MSA). This implementation delays the formation of the sulfate, changes the spatial distribution of sulfate aerosol, allows more time for the intermediates to undergo dry or wet deposition, and eventually reduces the effective sulfate yield from DMS. We explore whether a more comprehensive DMS oxidation scheme improves the ability of the model to capture observations of DMS, sulfate, and other relevant species from a series of airborne and in situ measurements. Finally, we perform a series of simulations under present-day and preindustrial climate and emission scenarios to characterize the impact of a more comprehensive DMS scheme on the estimation of aerosol indirect effect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
