<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CESM | Ka Ming Fung, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/tags/cesm/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/tags/cesm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CESM</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/media/icon_hu14322561806154635754.png</url>
      <title>CESM</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/tags/cesm/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the interinfluence of fertilizer-induced ammonia emission, nitrogen deposition, and aerosol radiative effects using modified CESM2</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Codes are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_NH3/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_NH3/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring dimethyl sulfide (DMS) oxidation and implications for global aerosol radiative forcing</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/fung-2022a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Codes are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_Heald_DMS/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/kamingfung/Fung_Heald_DMS/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responses of surface ozone to future agricultural ammonia emissions and subsequent nitrogen deposition through terrestrial ecosystem changes</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/liu-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/publication/liu-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CESM The Atmosphere, Whole Atmosphere, and Chemistry-Climate Working Group Meeting 2021</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2021-02-cam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2021-02-cam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring natural aerosol formation from DMS oxidation and implications for aerosol forcing&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU Fall Meeting 2020</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2020-12-agu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 07:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2020-12-agu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring natural aerosol formation from DMS oxidation and implications for aerosol forcing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atmospheric aerosol influences the Earth&amp;rsquo;s overall radiative balance, both directly via scattering and absorbing insolation or outgoing radiation reflected by the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface, and indirectly through promoting cloud formation and changing cloud properties. To quantify the radiative forcing requires the comparison of the net radiative budgets of a &amp;quot;polluted&amp;quot; atmosphere versus a &amp;quot;cleaner&amp;quot; preindustrial one. The accurate determination of aerosol radiative forcing thus partly depends on our ability to model the poorly understood preindustrial atmosphere. Here, we focus on modeling the oxidation of dimethyl sulfide (DMS) – a primary natural precursor of non-sea-salt sulfate. Based on previous laboratory studies, we extend the simple DMS oxidation scheme used in the Community Atmospheric Model with chemistry (CAM-chem) version 6 (and similarly in many global ESMs) by adding new gas- and aqueous-phase reactions and including intermediate compounds, e.g., methanesulfonic acid (MSA). This implementation delays the formation of the sulfate, changes the spatial distribution of sulfate aerosol, allows more time for the intermediates to undergo dry or wet deposition, and eventually reduces the effective sulfate yield from DMS. We explore whether a more comprehensive DMS oxidation scheme improves the ability of the model to capture observations of DMS, sulfate, and other relevant species from a series of airborne and in situ measurements. Finally, we perform a series of simulations under present-day and preindustrial climate and emission scenarios to characterize the impact of a more comprehensive DMS scheme on the estimation of aerosol indirect effect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CESM Land Model Working Group Meeting 2020</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2020-03-clm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2020-03-clm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impacts of Ammonia-Aerosol-Climate Feedbacks on Food Security and Air Quality&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU Fall Meeting 2019</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-12-agu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 11:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-12-agu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modeling ammonia-aerosol-climate feedback mechanisms using an earth system model: Implications for future food security and air quality&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCMI Science Workshop 2019</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-08-ccmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 10:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-08-ccmi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modeling and Assessing the Impacts of Sustainable Farming Practices on Food Security, Air Quality, and Public Health&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gordon Research Conference – Urbanization, Water and Food Security 2019</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-07-grc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 11:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-07-grc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-benefits of Intercropping, as a Sustainable Farming Practice, for Safeguarding Food Supply and Air Quality&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Talk for Centre for Atmospheric Science Seminars</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-05-uofcambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-05-uofcambridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modelling and Assessing the Impacts of Intercropping, as a Sustainable Farming Practice, on Food Security, Air Quality, and Public Health&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture is the major emitter of atmospheric ammonia (NH$_3$) in Europe, China, and the US (85$–$95%). This NH$_3$ is also attributable to approximately 20% of the fine particulate matter (PM$\_{2.5}$) formed, which harms human health in the neighbourhood areas. The fast-growing food production, due to the rising world population and their more meat-inclined dietary habits, could thus worsen the pollution problem. Previous field studies have shown that soybean intercropping can exploit the mutualistic interactions between crops to promote legume nitrogen fixation for enhancing crop yield, reducing fertiliser use, and thus diminishing NH$_3$ emission. In this study, we aim to investigate the potential benefit of large-scale intercropping on crop productivity, air quality, and public health. To quantify crop yield and NH$_3$ emission under intercropping, we implement into a soil biogeochemical model, DeNitrification-DeComposition (DNDC), a new scheme to parametrize the belowground interactions of intercropped crops. With the DNDC -simulated NH$_3$ emission, we predict the formation of downwind PM$\_{2.5}$ using a global 3-D chemical transport model, GEOS-Chem. We find that, if all Chinese farms are adopting maize-soybean intercropping, the same croplands which were initially for only maize or soybean can now produce both crops with comparable yields (90-100%) as their monoculture counterparts. The fertiliser use for intercropping is 42% lower, leading to a reduction in NH$_3$ emission by 45% and a drop in PM$\_{2.5}$ concentration by up to 2.3% (equivalent to 1.5 μg m$^{-3}$). This improvement can spare the Chinese government USD13 billion per year in air pollution-related health damage costs. Toward a better understanding on how regional conversion to sustainable farming alternatives may affect global climate and air quality, we are developing a process-based NH$_3$ volatilisation scheme and the parametrisation of crop-crop belowground interactions into the Community Earth System Model (CESM). We hope that our study can help policymakers to evaluate the costs and benefits of adopting sustainable alternatives and derive a science-based long-term strategy for food security and air pollution mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7th Annual Composition-Climate Interaction Meeting</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-03-acci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-03-acci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimation of agricultural ammonia emission under sustainable farming practices by improving terrestrial nitrogen cycle modeling&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Young Scientists Summit 2019</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-01-gyss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2019-01-gyss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-benefits of maize-soybean intercropping for securing air quality and global food supply&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU Fall Meeting 2018</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2018-12-agu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 16:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2018-12-agu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving the terrestrial N cycle modeling for a better estimation of agricultural ammonia emission under sustainable farming alternatives&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint 14th iCACGP Symposium and 15th IGAC Science Conference</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2018-09-igac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2018-09-igac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential co-benefits of intercropping as a sustainable agricultural practice for both air pollution mitigation and global food security&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sponsor&#34;&gt;Sponsor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel Grant and Selected Attendee of the Early Career Short Course, Joint 14th iCACGP Symposium &amp;amp; 15th IGAC Science Conference, IGAC Project&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CESM Land Model Working Group Meeting 2018</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2018-02-clm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2018-02-clm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large-scale adoption of intercropping for securing global food supply and air quality – a model study using CLM 4.5&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGU Fall Meeting 2017</title>
      <link>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2017-12-agu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kamingfung.github.io/kamingfung.github.io.academic_cv/talk/2017-12-agu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modeling large-scale adoption of intercropping as a sustainable agricultural practice for food security and air pollution mitigation around the globe&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
